<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- 
cached data at 16:13:31
cached id cf0161869a5c6a3183be2daff9cbbc49
-->
<rss version="2.0" 
		xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
		xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
		xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"><channel><atom:link href="http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/feeds/rss/incidents/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><title>InciWeb National Incidents</title><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov</link><description>Latest incident updates nationally</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2014 16:13:31 -06:00</pubDate><language>en-us</language><item><title>Soda Fire (Wildfire)</title><published>Fri, 31 Jan 2014 11:05:30 -06:00</published><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2014 11:05:30 -06:00</pubDate><georss:point>36.213888888889 -118.53166666667</georss:point><geo:lat>36.213888888889</geo:lat><geo:long>-118.53166666667</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/3765/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/3765/</guid><description>The Soda Fire located in the Golden Trout Wilderness in Sequoia National Forest was likely dampened in the recent storm. The Ponderosa community near the fire reports snowfall of 9 inches and a snowpack of 8 inches as of Friday morning. Once the storm clears a recon flight will be done to see if there are any hot spots that were not extinguished by rain and snow. Future actions will be based on observations from this next recon flight. The fire grew to 1274 acres since it was discovered on January 13th. This will be the last update to inciweb unless the fire activity</description></item><item><title>Elk Complex (Wildfire)</title><published>Thu, 30 Jan 2014 14:15:52 -06:00</published><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2014 14:15:52 -06:00</pubDate><georss:point>43.3575 -115.4475</georss:point><geo:lat>43.3575</geo:lat><geo:long>-115.4475</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/3616/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/3616/</guid><description>The majority of the burned area is now open to public use. Areas remaining closed to all use are in the Dog Creek watershed. Areas with restricted use are Danskin OHV area with only foot or horse use allowed; and Wilson Creek Trails with a similar allowed use. Motorized or mechanized use is prohibitied. The mud slides that occurred in mid-September have mostly stablized and dried but concern remains for the potential of addtional slides with any high rainfall event. All county roads are open. The Elk Complex Fire resulted from several lightning fires burning together on the night of August 8th. It was declared 100% contained on 8/31. The fire is in monitor/patrol status. Burned Area Emergency Response (BAER) activities are on-going with some road drainage work done some re-seeding along roadways done and a contract is nearly done for aerial seeding and mulching. Nearly 75% of the burned area had high to moderate burn severity. The remaining closure detailed information is described...</description></item><item><title>Tusayan Ranger District Prescribed Fire (Prescribed Fire)</title><published>Tue, 28 Jan 2014 17:01:15 -06:00</published><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2014 17:01:15 -06:00</pubDate><georss:point>35.980277777778 -112.15861111111</georss:point><geo:lat>35.980277777778</geo:lat><geo:long>-112.15861111111</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/3735/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/3735/</guid><description>  Tusayan South Rx: 323 acres complete. Russell Rx: 259 acres complete. Flying J Rx: 831 acres complete. Tentative burning plans for the week of January 26 2014 have been put on hold at this time. Tusayan East Rx: Tentative burning plans for the week of January 26 2014 have been placed on hold at this time.  Scott Rx: 567 acres complete. General Rx: Tusayan AZ – This year the Tusayan Ranger District has prescribed (Rx) fire plans for approximately 5 000 acres. However these numbers represent planned maximums while actual acres burned may be significantly less. Starting in early September fire managers will use prescribed fire as part of continuing efforts to improve forest health enhance public safety and return fire to a fire-adapted ecosystem. While Rx fire lowers the risk of severe wildfires on the forest there may be noticeable impacts such as smoke production. Before a Rx fire notification will be provided through multiple channels including; email news releases Forest fire...</description></item><item><title>Shf Prescribed Fire (Prescribed Fire)</title><published>Tue, 28 Jan 2014 16:54:31 -06:00</published><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2014 16:54:31 -06:00</pubDate><georss:point>40.566944444444 -123.01638888889</georss:point><geo:lat>40.566944444444</geo:lat><geo:long>-123.01638888889</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/3742/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/3742/</guid><description>Annually fire managers implement prescribed fire projects on the Shasta-Trinity National Forest. These projects are part of a fuels management program. Each project has specific objectives involving reduction of hazardous fuels. The forest fuels and vegetation management program analyzes techniques to treat areas using a combination of methods. One treatment option is mechanical thinning and application of prescribed fire to treat the residual slash. Following a mechanical thinning sites may be prepared for prescribed fire which can involve piling material or constructing firelines (boundaries) for a broadcast fire application. A few other tasks involved in a prescribed fire application include; preparing a prescribed fire plan assessing fuel conditions reviewing weather forecasts prior to ignition and setting up monitoring points. This briefly summarizes some of the prescribed fire aspects in the fire management program. The Shasta-Trinity National Forest generally conducts...</description></item><item><title>Williams Ranger District Prescribed Fire (Prescribed Fire)</title><published>Tue, 28 Jan 2014 16:41:51 -06:00</published><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2014 16:41:51 -06:00</pubDate><georss:point>35.309166666667 -111.93611111111</georss:point><geo:lat>35.309166666667</geo:lat><geo:long>-111.93611111111</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/3738/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/3738/</guid><description>Government Prairie Rx: Crews completed approximately 2 600 acres of prescribed fire in the Government Prairie project area 8 miles northeast of Parks AZ. Burn operations are complete at this time. McCracken Cougar Park Rx: 539 acres complete. Spring Valley Rx: 239 acres complete. City SE Rx: 158 acres complete. General Rx: This year the Williams Ranger District has prescribed (Rx) fire plans for approximately 13000 acres. However these numbers represent planned maximums while actual acres burned may be significantly less. Starting in early September fire managers will use prescribed fire as part of continuing efforts to improve forest health enhance public safety and return fire to a fire-adapted ecosystem. While Rx fire lowers the risk of severe wildfires on the forest there may be noticeable impacts such as smoke production. Before a Rx fire notification will be provided through multiple channels including; email news releases Forest fire information line Inciweb Twitter flyers and...</description></item><item><title>Colby (Wildfire)</title><published>Sat, 25 Jan 2014 14:17:35 -06:00</published><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2014 14:17:35 -06:00</pubDate><georss:point>34.158888888889 -117.84305555556</georss:point><geo:lat>34.158888888889</geo:lat><geo:long>-117.84305555556</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/3766/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/3766/</guid><description>Glendora Mountain and Ridge Roads</description></item><item><title>Campbell Fire (Wildfire)</title><published>Fri, 10 Jan 2014 13:20:13 -06:00</published><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2014 13:20:13 -06:00</pubDate><georss:point>40.066111111111 -121.76361111111</georss:point><geo:lat>40.066111111111</geo:lat><geo:long>-121.76361111111</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/3763/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/3763/</guid><description>Fire crews continue to patrol containment lines and perform mop-up operations and have begun rehabilitation in the Campbell Fire area located in the Ishi Wilderness of the Lassen National Forest north of the community of Campbellville in Tehama County. As of this morning acres burned on the Campbell Fire remain at approximately 865 and it remains at 90% contained. Fire officials anticipate it will be 100% contained by this evening. The area of the fire backing down to Deer Creek is the containment line and once it reaches the creek the fire should be fully contained. To aid in containment humidity levels have continued to rise and precipitation is forecast for the area. Three hand crews and one helicopter remain on the fire with more downsizing of resources expected later today. Although the immediate danger from this fire has decreased significantly other dangers still exist in the fire area such as hot spots in the interior fallen branches and hazard trees. The public should also...</description></item><item><title>Pfeiffer Fire (Wildfire)</title><published>Wed, 25 Dec 2013 16:42:01 -06:00</published><pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2013 16:42:01 -06:00</pubDate><georss:point>36.251944444444 -121.8</georss:point><geo:lat>36.251944444444</geo:lat><geo:long>-121.8</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/3761/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/3761/</guid><description>The Pfeiffer Fire started on December 17th 2013 around midnight in the vicinity of Pfeiffer Ridge in the Monterey Ranger District of Los Padres National Forest. The fire has burned 917 acres and is 100 percent contained. Thirty four (34) residence and 4 outbuildings have been damaged/destroyed. Damage assessment teams have completed their preliminary evaluation of damaged/destroyed property. The number of structures given reflect the structures documented as of December 20 2013. The fire was declared contained on December 20 2013 at 6:00 p.m. All evacuations and road closures have been lifted. Residents of Pfeiffer Ridge Road and Sycamore Canyon road were allowed to return to their residences on December 23 2013 at 6:00 p.m. Residents of Clear Creek Middle Ridge and Front Hill were allowed to return to their homes on December 21 2013.  Due to predicted increased temperatures but higher relative humidity fire activity inside the perimeter will be less during today's operational period....</description></item><item><title>Tunnel Hill (Prescribed Fire)</title><published>Tue, 17 Dec 2013 17:28:33 -06:00</published><pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2013 17:28:33 -06:00</pubDate><georss:point> -</georss:point><geo:lat></geo:lat><geo:long>-</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/3746/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/3746/</guid><description>Update: In just eight days of burning during November and early December the Sulphur Ranger District burned 6800 piles along the west and north facing slopes of Tunnel Hill completing those most prominint to the town's viewshed. Burning has wrapped up for the season due to deep snow and holidays. Pile burning may resume in the spring depending on conditions. Some 13000 piles remain to be burned in 2014. Summary: The U.S. Forest Service's Sulphur Ranger District is completing much-needed forest restoration on National Forest System lands bordering the Town of Winter Park. Over the past two years the Tunnel Hill Fuels Reduction project has been thinning and removing stands of unhealthy lodgepole pine on steeps slopes between town and the ski area. A wildfire in this area could be devastating to neighboring communities businesses infrastructure and watersheds. Denver Water the largest provider of municipal water to Colorado's densely populated Front Range is funding a large portion of...</description></item><item><title>Shasta-Trinity NF  Fall Storms (Flood)</title><published>Thu, 12 Dec 2013 18:35:03 -06:00</published><pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2013 18:35:03 -06:00</pubDate><georss:point> -</georss:point><geo:lat></geo:lat><geo:long>-</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/3313/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/3313/</guid><description>Effective today the Shasta-Trinity National Forest is excited to announce that Fenders Ferry Road (Forest Road No. 34N17) on the Shasta-Lake Ranger District is re-opened. Fenders Ferry had been closed due to damage sustained in the 2012 Bagley Fire and subsequent winter storms. The Bagley Fire Emergency Closure Order No. 14-12-02 has been amended to allow public access to part of the Bagley Fire Emergency Closure Area. Madrone Campground has also been re-opened. Deadlun Campground Ah-Di-Na Ash Camp and Fisherman’s Loop are also all open for public use. The repair work to Fenders Ferry and the Squaw Creek Bridge has now been completed however high clearance vehicles are still</description></item><item><title>South Fork Fire (Wildfire)</title><published>Thu, 05 Dec 2013 15:15:55 -06:00</published><pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2013 15:15:55 -06:00</pubDate><georss:point>38.789166666667 -78.425555555556</georss:point><geo:lat>38.789166666667</geo:lat><geo:long>-78.425555555556</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/3753/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/3753/</guid><description>Current Status: The South Fork Fire was reported on Monday November 18 2013. This fire was located fourteen miles north of Luray VA. It was north of Habron Gap south of Indian Grave Ridge and west of State Roads 684 and 717 in both Page and Shenandoah Counties. Acreage: 609 Acres Containment: As of December 1 2013 the fire is 100% contained Date and Cause Reported: The fire was reported on Monday November 18 2013 at 3:00 pm. The cause of the fire is unknown and under investigation. Cooperators: Virginia Department of Forestry; Virginia Department of Game and Inland Fisheries; Shenandoah County Fire and Rescue; Page County Fire and Rescue; Shenandoah National Park; Bureau of Indian Affairs; and US Fish and Wildlife Service. Restrictions and Closures: None General Fire Information: Homeowners can learn how to make their homes less susceptible to wildfires by visiting:</description></item><item><title>Table Rock (Wildfire)</title><published>Tue, 03 Dec 2013 12:10:31 -06:00</published><pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2013 12:10:31 -06:00</pubDate><georss:point>35.886388888889 -81.885833333333</georss:point><geo:lat>35.886388888889</geo:lat><geo:long>-81.885833333333</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/3752/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/3752/</guid><description>The Table Rock fire will be turned back over to the local unit Pisgah National Forest Grandfather Ranger District effective tomorrow morning. Contact for fire information has changed. The fire is still at 2 579 acres but containment changed to 90% yesterday. This will be the last update from the SA Type 2</description></item><item><title>Kern River Rd/Sequoia Prescribed Burns (Prescribed Fire)</title><published>Wed, 27 Nov 2013 12:32:18 -06:00</published><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2013 12:32:18 -06:00</pubDate><georss:point> -</georss:point><geo:lat></geo:lat><geo:long>-</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/3759/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/3759/</guid><description>Fire fighting personnel from the Kern River Ranger District are currently conducting a prescribed burn operation on National Forest lands adjacent to homes in Alta Sierra within the Greenhorn Mountains. In the past two weeks 140 acres have been burned adjacent to private property both east and west of Highway 155. Prescribed burning is being conducted in small individual units designed to minimize effects of smoke on the community while reducing the potential for large stand replacing wildfires. The project also serves to regenerate the forest and provide a diverse and important animal habitat for many species including deer bear and quail while maintain diversity for sensitive species such as goshawks fisher and spotted</description></item><item><title>South Rim Fall Rx Burns (Prescribed Fire)</title><published>Tue, 26 Nov 2013 15:15:16 -06:00</published><pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2013 15:15:16 -06:00</pubDate><georss:point>36.05 -112.2</georss:point><geo:lat>36.05</geo:lat><geo:long>-112.2</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/3745/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/3745/</guid><description>On Thursday November 21 South Rim Fire Managers began burning piles along Rowe Well Road between Maswik Laundry Road and Kennel Road; 10 acres were treated. An additional 20 acres were treated on Friday November 22. Fire managers expect to continue ignitions on Monday November 25 and hope to complete an additional 30 acres. Total Current South Rim Acerage:</description></item><item><title>High Glade Fire (Wildfire)</title><published>Tue, 26 Nov 2013 12:42:37 -06:00</published><pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2013 12:42:37 -06:00</pubDate><georss:point>39.245833333333 -122.81</georss:point><geo:lat>39.245833333333</geo:lat><geo:long>-122.81</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/3756/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/3756/</guid><description>UPPER LAKE Calif. – The High Glade Fire currently burning on the Upper Lake Ranger District of the Mendocino National Forest is 305 acres and 70 percent contained. Full containment is expected by the end of the week. The reduction in acres is due to more complete and accurate mapping of the fire perimeter. Smoke will still be visible as interior fuels continue to burn. Visitors are asked to avoid the area due to increased fire traffic. Several roads are closed in the area. Please visit www.fs.usda.gov/mendocino to view Closure Order 08-13-09 for more detailed information. The High Glade Fire was spotted early Saturday morning. The cause of the fire is under investigation. This will be the final update unless significant activity occurs. For more information please contact the Mendocino National Forest at 530-934-3316 or visit www.fs.usda.gov/mendocino. Updates will also be available on Inciweb at www.inciweb.org or on Twitter @Mendocino NF.</description></item><item><title>Landfill Fire (Wildfire)</title><published>Fri, 22 Nov 2013 09:16:04 -06:00</published><pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2013 09:16:04 -06:00</pubDate><georss:point>36.805555555556 -81.135277777778</georss:point><geo:lat>36.805555555556</geo:lat><geo:long>-81.135277777778</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/3749/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/3749/</guid><description>Location: The Landfill Fire is located on the north slope of Horse Heaven Mountain approximately one mile south of the town of Speedwell in Wythe County. It is east of Highway 21 and south of the Speedwell Landfill.  Estimated Acreage: Approximately 1507 acres Containment: 85% contained  Overview: The Landfill Fire will be fully contained as of end of shift Friday November 22. Firefighters will continue suppression efforts within the interior of the fire in the coming days. Rehabilitation of constructed hand and dozer line will continue until all necessary repairs have been made. The Area Closure has been reduced in size as of Friday; however the Area Closure remains in effect. Please see Closure Information below. The public is reminded to be cautious while driving as fire personnel will remain in the area for the coming days.   Fire Cause: The fire was reported late Tuesday night November 12 2013. The cause of the fire is under investigation. Resources on the Fire: Approximately 75...</description></item><item><title>Prescribed Burn (Prescribed Fire)</title><published>Thu, 21 Nov 2013 11:27:33 -06:00</published><pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2013 11:27:33 -06:00</pubDate><georss:point> -</georss:point><geo:lat></geo:lat><geo:long>-</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/3754/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/3754/</guid><description>The Stanislaus National Forest will be conducting prescribed burns on the forest. Cooler temperatures and rain are expected in the next several days which will provide conditions conducive for burning. Burning is contingent on weather fuel moisture and air quality. All burning is monitored and conducted in accordance with state and county air quality guidelines and closely coordinated with local county air quality control districts. Smoke may be visible along the Highway 108 corridor.  CLICK HERE for the latest information.</description></item><item><title>North Rim Fall Rx Burns (Prescribed Fire)</title><published>Tue, 19 Nov 2013 16:25:38 -06:00</published><pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2013 16:25:38 -06:00</pubDate><georss:point>36.208611111111 -112.05777777778</georss:point><geo:lat>36.208611111111</geo:lat><geo:long>-112.05777777778</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/3743/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/3743/</guid><description>November 19 2013 The North Rim Slopes Rx has currently completed ingitition. Over two days 51 acres were treated. Fire behavoir was minimal with moderate smoke impacts. Smoke may still be visible for the next few days. November 17 2013 The North Rim Slopes Prescribed Fire (North Rim Slopes Rx) is located just west of Highway 67 and south of the Kaibab National Forest boundary. Fire managers anticipate initiating the North Rim Slopes Rx on Monday November 18th and expect to complete ignitions on Wednesday November 20th should conditions remain favorable. Ignitions are anticipated to last two to three days with several days or weeks of residual smoke to follow. The primary treatment area consists of Ponderosa pine and mixed conifer</description></item><item><title>Elephant Fire (Wildfire)</title><published>Wed, 13 Nov 2013 16:41:38 -06:00</published><pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2013 16:41:38 -06:00</pubDate><georss:point>37.733333333333 -79.35</georss:point><geo:lat>37.733333333333</geo:lat><geo:long>-79.35</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/3345/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/3345/</guid><description> Updates for the Elephant Fire will end on April 18, 2013. Location: The Elephant Fire is located on Elephant Mountain, just east of Buena Vista, Virginia Estimated Acreage: Approximately 256 acres Containment: 100% contained Operational Plan: For Wednesday, April 17, 2013, firefighters will look to finalize containment efforts of the Elephant Fire, and will continue mop-up of interior hotspots. Full containment of the Elephant Fire is expected today. Demobilization of fire resources is currently underway. Fire Cause: The Elephant Fire was initially reported at 4:30 p.m. on Sunday, April 14, 2013. The cause of the fire is under investigation. Resources on the Fire: Approximately 55 firefighters and support staff, including one Type 1 Hotshot Crew, and two engines are assisting with the Elephant Fire. Closures: No closures at this time Cooperators: Virginia Department of Forestry, National Park Service, Buena Vista Fire Department Fire Weather: -Wednesday Weather: Variable clouds with...</description></item><item><title>Rim Post-Fire BAER (Burned Area Emergency Response)</title><published>Wed, 13 Nov 2013 13:24:49 -06:00</published><pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2013 13:24:49 -06:00</pubDate><georss:point> -</georss:point><geo:lat></geo:lat><geo:long>-</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/3726/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/3726/</guid><description>  To access the Rim BAER Specialists reports click http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/article/3726/21596/. Most recent photos of BAER implementation work are posted here: http://delivr.com/2d2a7 The National Weather Service has been working with the the CA-NV River Forecast Center and the United States Geological Survey to develop precipitation thresholds that will likely trigger debris flows rock slides ash movement and flash floods on the Rim Fire burn scar. These are the initial values we will be utilizing going into this winter. .2&quot; in 15 minutes .3&quot; in 30 minutes .5&quot; in 1 hour .9&quot; in 3 hours 1.4&quot; in 6 hours For public safety the Rim Fire closure is still in effect. Please abide by the closure signs. Crews and equipment are working in the area creating a hazardous situation. Burned trees continue to fall. For more information select the closure tab above. The Burned Area Emergency Response (BAER) implementation team continues to assess needs and implement emergency stabilization...</description></item><item><title>Ken (Wildfire)</title><published>Wed, 13 Nov 2013 10:03:40 -06:00</published><pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2013 10:03:40 -06:00</pubDate><georss:point>34.240277777778 -117.41222222222</georss:point><geo:lat>34.240277777778</geo:lat><geo:long>-117.41222222222</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/3748/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/3748/</guid><description>A series of small fires erupted at 4:30PM along the right shoulder of northbound Interstate 15 north of the Kenwood exit on Tuesday afternoon. Initially the fire had a moderate rate of spread and was threatening homes in the area. An immediate decisive and aggressive attack by firefighters from the Forest Service CAL FIRE San Bernardino County and San Bernardino City Fire responded and held the fire at seven acres. CalTrans and the California Highway Patrol closed the right two lanes on the freeway due to the fire during Tuesday evening. Forest Service night flying Air Attack and night flying helicopter responded to the incident to provide support to firefighters on the ground. The cause of the fire remains under</description></item><item><title>Whiskey Complex (Wildfire)</title><published>Mon, 11 Nov 2013 14:08:14 -06:00</published><pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2013 14:08:14 -06:00</pubDate><georss:point>42.941111111111 -122.82166666667</georss:point><geo:lat>42.941111111111</geo:lat><geo:long>-122.82166666667</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/3562/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/3562/</guid><description>The four fires of the Whiskey Complex were ignited by lightning on July 26th. The Whiskey Buckeye and Smith Ridge fires were fully contained on August 24. The Smith Ridge fire was declared out at 23 acres on September 7th. Many smokes remain visible within the perimeter of the Whiskey Fire while the Buckeye Fire has only a few hot spots that are being monitored. The Tiller Ranger District is managing the complex of fires under the direction of Incident Commander Drew DeLozier as of Monday September 16th at 6</description></item><item><title>Helena Prescribed Burns (Prescribed Fire)</title><published>Wed, 06 Nov 2013 13:24:37 -06:00</published><pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2013 13:24:37 -06:00</pubDate><georss:point> -</georss:point><geo:lat></geo:lat><geo:long>-</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/2818/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/2818/</guid><description>As weather fuel moisture and air quality conditions allow the Helena Ranger District plans to implement various prescribed burning projects across the District this fall and early winter. Several units totaling about 200 acres within the Clancy-Unionville Vegetation and Travel Management Project are planned this year. These planned low-intensity prescribed burns will help improve forest health in our fire-dependent ecosystems by helping create more native plant and tree diversity regarding species ages and sizes. This diversity improves the forest’s resiliency and sustainability from various threats including insects diseases and large high-intense wildfires. The Clancy-Unionville prescribed fire project is a compilation of multiple fire units which means it will take more than one ignition to complete the 200-acre prescribed burn this fall/winter. Multiple slash piles across the District are also scheduled to be burned this year. The slash piles are a result of hazardous fuels...</description></item><item><title>Townsend Prescribed Burns (Prescribed Fire)</title><published>Wed, 06 Nov 2013 13:23:40 -06:00</published><pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2013 13:23:40 -06:00</pubDate><georss:point> -</georss:point><geo:lat></geo:lat><geo:long>-</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/2817/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/2817/</guid><description>As weather fuel moisture and air quality conditions allow the Townsend Ranger District plans to implement various prescribed burning projects in both the Big Belt Mountains and Elkhorn Mountains this fall and early winter. Some slash piles across the District may be burned as well. Several units totaling about 200 acres within the Crow Creek Vegetation Management Project are planned to move the area toward a more desired vegetation condition for wildlife scenery recreation and livestock grazing by introducing low-intense prescribed fire to the landscape. The burns will help minimize conifer encroachment and help reestablish native plants within this ecosystem. Nearly 100 acres in the Pole Creek area of the Elkhorn Mountains are scheduled to be burned to reduce conifer encroachment and revitalize the grassland ecosystems on the Pole Creek grazing allotment. Various slash piles across the District may be burned this year as well. Slash piles in the Duck Creek Gypsy Lake and Atlanta...</description></item><item><title>Lincoln Prescribed Burns (Prescribed Fire)</title><published>Tue, 05 Nov 2013 17:18:10 -06:00</published><pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2013 17:18:10 -06:00</pubDate><georss:point> -</georss:point><geo:lat></geo:lat><geo:long>-</geo:long><link>http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/2816/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://inciweb.nwcg.gov/incident/2816/</guid><description>Lincoln Ranger District Prescribed Burns The Lincoln Ranger District of the Helena National Forest plans to implement prescribed burns this spring and/or early summer as long as the desired weather fuel moisture and smoke dispersal conditions are met. Lincoln District Compound: Low-intense maintenance burning—similar to what occurred this spring—is scheduled on 37 acres located across the Highway from the Ranger District office. The purpose of this burn is to reduce the fine fuel loading and promote native grasses. Alice Creek: One 40-acre unit in the upper end of Alice Creek is scheduled to be burned for the purpose of enhancing big game forage and reducing hazardous fuel conditions. This project is a joint effort between the Rocky Mountain Elk Foundation and the Helena National Forest. Poorman Creek: One 300-acre unit called “Ethel 22” is scheduled to be burned this fall when conditions allow. The purpose of this is to help improve forest health and reduce hazardous fuel...</description></item></channel></rss>